Guide to the Michael Ivanovitch Rostovtzeff Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Michael Ivanovitch Rostovtzeff papers
1914-1952
MS 1133
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
13.25
(34 boxes)
The papers consist of manuscripts, notes, lectures, photographs, and miscellanea documenting the professional career of Michael I. Rostovtzeff, an archaeologist, professor of ancient history, and director of archaeological studies at Yale University, 1914-1952. Manuscripts and notes contain drafts and research data for Rostovtzeff's major literary works; photographs detail many antiquities and artifacts related to ancient history; lectures contain several papers on archaeological and historical topics, including the Dura Europos excavations in Syria.
Rostovtzeff, Michael Ivanovitch, 1870-1952
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The major portion of these papers were previously in the Dura Europos Papers which have been transferred to the Yale Art Gallery.
Associated Materials
Related material: Dura-Europos Collection, (Yale Art Gallery, Yale University.)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
I. Manuscripts and Notes 1922-1944. II. Photographs ca. 1914-1938. III. Lectures, 1920-1944. IV. Writings and Miscellanea, 1914-1952.
Scope and Contents
The Mikhail I. Rostovtzeff Papers document the professional career of Mikhail I. Rostovtzeff, an archaelogist, professor of ancient history, and director of archaeological studies at Yale University, The Rostovtzeff Papers consist of thirteen and one-quarter linear feet of material arranged in thirty-four boxes. Rostovtzeff's manuscripts, notes, lectures, photographs, and miscellanea have span dates of 1914-1952, with much of the material undated. Correspondence with academic colleagues, family members, and others is notably absent from the Rostovtzeff Papers.
The Rostovtzeff Papers are arranged in four series: I. Manuscripts and Notes 1922-1944. II. Photographs ca. 1914-1938. III. Lectures, 1920-1944. IV. Writings and Miscellanea, 1914-1952.
Series I, MANUSCRIPTS AND NOTES, consists of handwritten and typescript drafts and research information for many of Rostovtzeff's books. These materials were written in a variety of languages, including English, French, and Greek. The series is arranged in the following sections: Hellenistic period - manuscripts, Hellenistic period - notes, Hellenistic period - Social and Economic History, and General.
Hellenistic period - manuscripts contains a group of article or chapter-length essays on several aspects of the Hellenistic period in Greek culture, which dates from the empires of Alexander the Great, the Antigonids, the Seleucids, and the Ptolemies until the eastern conquests of Rome. The writings are heavily annotated and include essays on "The Hellenistic World and Its Economic Development" (folders 3-4) and "The Mentality of the Hellenistic World and the Afterlife " (folder 6). The numerous drafts and revision of these manuscripts suggest that multiple uses of the material—in books, articles, lectures, and other pursuits—were possible.
Hellenistic period - notes is a four box section (boxes 2-5) of research information Rostovtzeff accumulated in the course of his professional career. Notes on the many nations and nation-states active during the period are present, including Egypt (folders 19-21), Italy (folder 25), Macedonia (folder 26), the Ptolemaic empire (folders 35-41), and the Seleucid empire (folders 43-45). The bulk of these notes are in foreign languages and appear to be information Rostovtzeff culled from printed sources during his literary research.
Hellenistic period - Social and Economic History contains Rostovtzeff's drafts and notes for one of his major literary works, Social and Economic History of the Hellenistic World, published in 1941. Folders sixty-four through seventy-one contain information relating to illustrations (plates) used in the volume. Rostovtzeff's collection of photographs for this work is arranged in Series II.
General contains an alphabetical arrangement of topical files on such subjects as: China, Decorative wall painting, Dura Europus, Egypt, Parthia, Roman Empire, Samartian period, Scythia, Seleucid Babylonia, and Social and Economic History of the Roman Empire.
Series II, PHOTOGRAPHS, is, arranged in two components: Section A and Section B. This maintains the original order of the material. Each section contains photographs of ancient antiquities, art, buildings, coins, drawings, excavations, jewels, objects, and miscellanea. The bulk of these are professional photographs of artifacts as they would appear in a museum setting. Rostovtzeff's notes on particular photographs are arranged with these materials. Cross-reference citations for those topics of common occurence in Section A and Section B are provided.
Photographs in this series are arranged under headings similar to those used in Series I. Thus, files for the Hellenistic period (Section A, folders 18-37) contain photographs of items from that era and correspond to Rostovtzeff's manuscripts and notes on the topic arranged in Series I. The largest groups of photographs in this series are: Italy, Rome (folders 44-49), Roman Empire (folders 63-68), Social and Economic History of the Hellenistic World (folders 73-75), and Russia (folders 128-136). Files for Social and Economic History of the Roman Empire. contain prints of photographs published and considered for publication in that volume (See also: Series I, folders 160-167).
Series III, LECTURES, contains a collection of Rostovtzeff's academic and public lectures [ca. 1920-1944]. Lectures from the University of Wisconsin (folders 165-168) date from 1920-1924. Course outlines and syllabi are included with this material. The focus of these lectures is on ancient history, especially the Roman empire and South Russia.
Lectures arranged under the heading "Yale University and other institutions" (folders 169-195) date from 1925-1944, n.d., and include a wide range of historical and archaeological topics. Among the popular topics for lectures are: the Orient, Greece, Iran and Iranian art, decorative arts, and Dura Europos. A series of notes for eight lectures delivered at the Norwegian Academy of Science in Oslo (1928) are also arranged in this series (folder 175). A small group of "Public Lectures" apparently delivered outside the academic community is arranged in box thirty-one.
Series IV, WRITINGS AND MISCELLLANEA contains a group of writings by Rostovtzeff and others. These materials do not appear to relate directly to his published volumes. Miscellaneous articles, bibliographic notes, and book reviews are arranged in this series (folders 200-207). Addition files in this series include writings on Dura Europos (folders 211-213), Iran (folders 219-220), the Near East (folders 234-235), and Palmyra (folder 236).
The Rostovtzeff Papers were donated to Yale University by Mikhail I. Rostovtzeff in 1942 and 1947. Other collections known to contain material by or about Mikhail I. Rostovtzeff include: Ellsworth Huntington Papers (Mss. Gr. No. 1), Wallace Notestein Papers (Mss. Gr. No. 544), and Clarence W. Mendell (Mss. Gr. No. 799).
The Yale Art Gallery houses the records of Dura Europos, an archaeological expedition which Rostovtzeff directed from 1928-1938.
Biographical / Historical
Michael Ivanovitch Rostovtzeff was born in Kiev, Russia, on November 10, 1870. He taught ancient history at the University of Wisconsin, 1920-1925, and Yale University, 1925-1939, where he also served as director of archaeological research and curator of ancient art, 1939-1944. Rostovtzeff died in New Haven, Connecticut, on October 20, 1952. He studied at the University of Kiev and the University of Saint Petersburg, 1888-1892, and the University of Vienna and German Archaeological Institute in Rome, 1895-1898. Rostovtzeff received his M.A. and Ph.D in Classical Philology from Saint Petersburg in 1899 and 1903. As an international scholar, Rostovtzeff travelled extensively and published works in several languages, including Greek, French and English. His works on the Dura Europos excavations are extensive. Rostovtzeff also served as president of the American Historical Association in 1935. He married Sophie Michailovna in Saint Petersburg, Russia, on May 8, 1901.
Archaeological expeditions; Archaeology; Classical antiquities; Classical education; Excavations (Archaeology) -- Syria -- Dura-Europos (Extinct city); Dura (Syria); Archaeologists; Classicists; Historians; Dura-Europos Papers; Rostovtzeff, Michael Ivanovitch, 1870-1952; Yale University -- Faculty
- Manuscripts and Notes, 1922-1944, undated; Series I; 6.75 linear feet (17 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged in four sections: Hellenistic period - manuscripts, Hellenistic period - notes, Hellenistic period - Social and Economic History, and General.
  Hellenistic period - manuscripts is a chronological arrangement of writings from 1930-1944, n.d.
  Hellenistic period - notes is an alphabetical arrangement of largely undated topical files.
  Hellenistic period - Social and Economic History contain drafts of Rostovtzeff's book, arranged by chapter, with miscellaneous material filed at the end of the section.
  General is an alphabetical arrangement of topical files or a variety of subjects.
  - Hellenistic period - manuscripts
    - Pergaman (?), 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Mithradates and the Pontus", 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "The Hellenistic World and Its Economic Development", 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - "Some Remarks on India and Its Early Art", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "The Mentality of the Hellenistic World and the afterlife", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Alexander the Great", 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Rhodes and Delos", undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Rome, Ptolemaic Egypt, and Asia Minor, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - L'Hellenisme en Mesopotamie, undated (Box 1, Folder 9A)
  - Hellenistic period - notes
    - Asia Minor - cities, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Balkan Peninsula, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cappadocia Pontus, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Celts, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Coinage, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - General economic evolution, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Foreign policy, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - The Mainland of Greece, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Greek Islands - Delos, Cyprus, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Hellenistic Egypt, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Hellenistic Egypt - Philadelphus, undated (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
    - Hellenistic Egypt [Euergetes I, Philopatus, Epiphanus, Philemeter, Euergetes II, and later], undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Hellenistic history (Spring 1941) cont. of B. Welle's course, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Macedonia, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Navigation, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Metalware, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Mithridates, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Pergamon - army & navy, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Pergamon - cities and provinces, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Pergamon - religion, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Pergamon - resources, kings, court, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Poetry and glass, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Political history, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Ptolemaic Commerce - The Morinces, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Ptolemaic Commerce - Commerce with the West and the Greek lands, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Ptolemaic Commerce - The Orient and the Smith, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Ptolemaic Commerce - Commerce in grain, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Ptolemaic Commerce - Organization, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Ptolemaic Egypt - The King and the Officials/The Army, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Rhodes - notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Seleucids - Babylonia, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Seleucids - Palestine and Phoenicia, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - The Seleucid Kingdom—General aims and evolutions, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Seleucids - Royal Power. Army, Navy, Economics, Administration, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Seleucids - General, Syria, Mesopotamia, Media, India, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Seleucids - Asia Minor, Milefus, Epheses, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Syria - addendum, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Ways and means of warfare, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Hellenistic period - Social & Economic History
    - Chapter notes
      - Chapters I, II, III, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Chapters IV - VI—Egypt - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Chapter- IV—Egypt - plates, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Chapter VIII—Architecture notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - Chapter VIII—Geography, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Chapter VIII—Notes, misc., undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - Chapter VIII—Population, Capital Sources of Wealth, Trade and Banking, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - Chapter VIII—Professions: Law, Doctors, Lawyers, Actors., undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - Chapter VIII—Religion, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
      - Chapter VIII—Schools, Gymnasium, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - Chapter VIII—Science, Technique, Machines, undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
      - Chapter VIII—Social Conditions, Mentality, Philosophy Theories, undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - Chapter VIII—Social Relations, Associations, undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Miscellaneous notes and plates
      - Greece and Macedonia - ;notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
      - on and Asia Minor - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 65)
      - Seleucid Kingdom - plates, undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
      - Syria - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
      - Feracottas and bronzes - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 68)
      - Miscellaneous notes and plates, undated (Box 7, Folder 69-71)
    - General
      - Ancient history
        - Orient and Greece, notes on illustrations, undated (Box 8, Folder 72)
        - Notes, photos, letters, undated (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - China
      - Notes - Art & Han Dynasty, undated (Box 8, Folder 74)
      - Notes and letters, undated (Box 8, Folder 75)
      - Proofs of plate - Le centre de l'Asie, la Russie, la Chine, et le Style Animal, undated (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Decorative wall painting - notes
      - Architecture and decorative painting, undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
      - Egypt, undated (Box 8, Folder 78)
      - Rome, undated (Box 8, Folder 79)
      - Rome and Pompeii, undated (Box 8, Folder 80)
      - Wall paintings, I Style, Outside of Pompeii, undated (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Dura Europos - manuscripts
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8, Folder 82-84)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 9, Folder 85-89)
    - Egypt (Ptolemaic)
      - Manuscript - Russian, bibliography, undated (Box 9, Folder 90)
      - Manuscript - foreign commerce, undated (Box 9, Folder 91)
      - Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - History of the Ancient World
      General
      See: box 13, folder Box 13
    - Parthia - manuscripts
      - The Parthian Shot, undated (Box 10, Folder 94-95)
      - Documetary Evidence on the Parthian Empire, undated (Box 10, Folder 96)
      - Dura and the problem of Parthian Art, undated (Box 10, Folder 97-100)
      - Dura and the problem of Parthian Art (3rd draft), undated (Box 10, Folder 101-102)
      - "Parthian Art and the Motive of the Flying Gallop", 1936 (Box 10, Folder 103)
      - Chapter III - Cambridge Ancient, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 104)
    - Parthia - notes
      - Art, undated (Box 11, Folder 105-107)
      - Organization, civilization, undated (Box 11, Folder 108)
      - Political history, undated (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - Roman Empire - manuscripts
      General note
      See also: box 22, folder 73
      - Economic life, Roman Republic, undated (Box 11, Folder 110)
      - Economic life, Roman Empire (Box 11, Folder 110)
      - Near East, undated (Box 11, Folder 111)
      - Vexillum and Victory, undated (Box 11, Folder 112)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - Roman Empire - notes (Box 11)
      - General, undated (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - Additions - economic policy, undated (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Addition to German edition, undated (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Additions to Italian version, undated (Box 12, Folder 117)
      - Africa, Cyrene, Tripoli, undated (Box 12, Folder 118)
      - Balbilus, undated (Box 12, Folder 119)
      - Cities, undated (Box 12, Folder 120)
      - Country, undated (Box 12, Folder 121)
      - Emperor, undated (Box 12, Folder 122)
      - Hadrian & M. Aurelius, undated (Box 12, Folder 123)
      - Provinces, Country, undated (Box 12, Folder 124)
      - Roman Africa, undated (Box 12, Folder 125)
      - Roman Egypt, undated (Box 12, Folder 126)
      - Roman provinces, undated (Box 12, Folder 127)
      - Roman Syria, undated (Box 12, Folder 128)
      - Rome and Sicily, undated (Box 12, Folder 129)
      - Notes - Misc. (Box 12, Folder 130)
    - Russia - manuscripts
      See also: Series II, folder 128-136
      - History of the Ancient World Text, Berlin, the Orient, p. proofs, 1923 1923 (Box 13, Folder 131)
      - History of the Ancient World Text, Berlin/Rome part I, p. proofs, 1923 1923 (Box 13, Folder 132)
      - History of the Ancient World Text, Berlin/Rome part II, p. proofs, 1923 1923 (Box 13, Folder 133)
      - History of the Ancient World Text, Berlin/Greece, p. proofs, 1923 1923 (Box 13, Folder 134)
      - South Russia and China, two centres of the development of the Animal Style, 1922 1922 (Box 13, Folder 135)
      - Animal Style in South Russia and China/Princeton University Press, 1929 1929 (Box 13, Folder 136)
      - Notes - "A gold necklace & gold armlet…", 1933 1933 (Box 13, Folder 137)
      - 1) Hellenism in South Russia - lecture, undated (Box 14, Folder 138)
      - 2) Greek & Oriental Art in South Russia—lecture—typescripts (Box 14, Folder 138)
      - Political articles about Russia, undated (Box 14, Folder 139)
      - Some materials on Science in South Russia, n.d n.d (Box 14, Folder 140)
    - Russia - notes
      - South Russia - bibliography, undated (Box 14, Folder 141)
      - South Russia - Bosporus-notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 142)
      - Lectures on South Russian Art, Princeton, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 143)
      - South Russia - Goths & Alans, undated (Box 14, Folder 144)
      - South Russia - maps, undated (Box 14, Folder 145)
      - South Russia - political history, bibliography, notes, sources, undated (Box 14, Folder 146)
      - South Russia - Scythia, literary Sources, undated (Box 14, Folder 147)
    - Samartian period
      - Notes - archaeology, undated (Box 15, Folder 148)
      - Sarmatians - notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 149)
      - Kuban, undated (Box 15, Folder 150)
      - Sarmatia - notes: Polychrome style, undated (Box 15, Folder 151)
      - Manuscript: The Samarte, undated (Box 15, Folder 152)
    - Scythia antiquities, undated (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - Scythia life, undated (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - Scythia - notes: Scythians and Hittites, undated (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - Scythia - notes: Scythia and the Bosporus, Religion, undated (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Scythia - maps: The Scythia of Herodotus and the Samartia of Stabo, undated (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Seleucid Babylonia - manuscript, undated (Box 15, Folder 158-159)
  - Social & Economic History of the Roman Empire
    See also: box 21, folder 63
    - Manuscript Additions, undated (Box 16, Folder 160)
    - Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 161)
    - Notes (3), undated (Box 16, Folder 162-164)
    - Notes - Roman Republic (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - Livy (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - Third Decade, undated (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - Notes - The military anarchy, undated (Box 16, Folder 167)
  - Syria and the East
    - Manuscript (in Russian) (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 16, Folder 168)
  - Uruk Bullae - Notes
    - Two negatives (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - Oxford, Copenhagen, Louvre, Brussels, undated (Box 16, Folder 169)
  - Uruk Werka - Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Zeno Papyri - Notes/Revisions in Oxford, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 171)
  - Zeno and Tebtunis 703 - Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 172)
  - Zeo Papyri - DWPEL of Apollonius, undated (Box 17, Folder 173)
  - Zeno Papyri - Notes/First And Second Period, undated (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Zeno Papyri - Notes/Third Period-Zeno & the officials, undated (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - Zeno Papyri - Notes/Fourth Period (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 17, Folder 177)
- Photographs, [ca. 1914-1938, undated]; Series II; 4 linear feet (10 boxes)
  This series is organized in two sections: Section A and Section B. Each section is alphabetically arranged by topic. The original organization and descriptive folder labels have been maintained for this series.
  - Section A
    - Africa - Cyrene, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      See also: box 23, folder 83
    - Anatolia bronzes, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - China - art, undated (Box 18, Folder 3-8)
      See also: box 23, folders 89-93
    - China - objects, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
      See also: box 23, folder 94-95
    - China and Scythia - objects, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - China and South Russia - Art, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Cypria - horsemen, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Decorative wall painting, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Decorative wall painting - misc., undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Egypt, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Greco - Persian Art, undated (Box 18, Folder 16-17)
    - Hellenistic Period
      - Afghanistan, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Asia Minor, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Asia Minor - Pergamon, undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Athens, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Coins, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Delos, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Louvre, undated (Box 19, Folder 24-25)
      - Miscellaneous, 1926-1928, undated (Box 19, Folder 26-30)
      - Museums, artwork, undated (Box 19, Folder 31)
      - Objects, undated (Box 19, Folder 32)
      - Pottery (Oriental Institute of Chicago), undated (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - Russia - South Russia, undated (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - Syria, undated (Box 19, Folder 35-37)
    - Hittite antiquities, undated (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - India antiquities, undated (Box 20, Folder 39-43)
    - Italy, Rome
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20, Folder 44-45)
      - Museum of Bari, undated (Box 20, Folder 46)
      - Museum of Capua, undated (Box 20, Folder 47)
      - Museum of Reggio, undated (Box 20, Folder 48)
      - Statues, undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Lauristan bronzes, undated (Box 20, Folder 50-51)
    - Miscellaneous - coins, undated (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - Mitanni bronzes, undated (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - Mithra, undated (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Palmyra (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - Parthia
      - Art, undated (Box 21, Folder 56-57)
      - Horsemen, undated (Box 21, Folder 58)
      - Objects, undated (Box 21, Folder 59)
    - Persia - art, undated (Box 21, Folder 60-61)
      See also: box 25, folder 124
    - Roman Britain, undated (Box 21, Folder 62)
    - Roman Empire
      - Antiquities, undated (Box 21, Folder 63)
      - China & Egypt, undated (Box 21, Folder 64)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 21, Folder 65-66)
      - Museum of Cairo, undated (Box 21, Folder 67)
      - Nubia, undated (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - Roman provinces, undated (Box 22, Folder 69)
    - Russia - South Russia, undated (Box 22, Folder 70)
      See also: box 25, folder 128-136
    - Samartia - antiquities, undated (Box 22, Folder 71)